<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HOSTIFY</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Setting</string>
    <string name="abyssiniainfo"><b>Abyssinia Renaissance Hotel\n</b>\nAbyssinia Renaissance Hotel is One of the bestsellers in Addis Ababa!"Offering a terrace and views of the mountains.\n\nAbyssinia Renaissance Hotel is located in Addis Ababa. The hotel has a spa centre and sauna, and guests can enjoya drink at the bar. Free WiFi is available throughout the property and free private parking is available on site."\n\nThe rooms come with a TV with satellite channels. All rooms have a desk and seating area where you can relax. You will finda kettle in the room. All rooms are fitted with a private bathroom. For your comfort, you will find bath robes, slippers and free toiletries.

        There is free shuttle service at the property.\n
        The hotel also offers car hire. The nearest airport is Addis Ababa Bole International Airport, 2 km from Abyssinia
        Renaissance Hotel.\n\n
        <b>Bole is a great choice for travellers interested in nightlife, culture and warm weather.</b>
        \n
        <b>We speak your language!</b>
    </string>

    <string name="hiltoninfo"><b>Hilton Addis Ababa</b>\n\n

        Hilton Addis Ababa is located in a hub of international diplomacy, just 15 minutes from Bole International Airport. The hotel is also close to United Nations Economic Commission for Africa, the African Union and many of the city\'s most popular attractions. Enjoy the geo-thermal outdoor swimming pool, a squash court, and an 18-hole mini-golf course. Parking is available for more than 650 cars.

With six distinctive restaurants and bars, Hilton Addis Ababa offers an enticing range of cuisines and settings, including the popular poolside Sunday brunch with live music and rustic wood-fired specialties from Il Forno.

Blending traditional Ethiopian touches with contemporary style, Hilton Addis Ababa was designed to mirror the famous Lalibella Cross, and the motif is recurrent throughout the hotel. All 372 hotel rooms offer pool or mountain views, original artwork, comfortable sleeping areas and ample work space. Choose a suite or Executive Floor room for more space and access to the Executive Lounge. For extended stays, book a studio, one- or two- bedroom apartment with its own kitchen.

Host a board meeting for 25 delegates in one of three meeting rooms, or for a larger event, the ballroom accommodates more than 800 Guests. Event support Team Members provide bespoke planning, coordination and catering services. After a day of work or sightseeing, retreat to the Health Club for a soothing sauna or steam, or book a relaxing massage.
        Hilton Addis Ababa is situated in the heart of the political capital of Africa.\n
        This landmark hotel in Ethiopia, which is inspired by the famous Lalibella Cross Church, is the only hotel
        with geo-thermal outdoor swimming pool, an 18-hole mini golf, a squash court and a parking space for more than
        650 cars. This unique hotel in Ethiopia is set on 15 acres of lush foliage, surrounded by expansive gardens.
        Hilton Addis Ababa is located near the ECA Convention Center in the city center and is only 15 minutes from Bole
        International Airport.\n
  
            • Scheduled shuttle available\n
            • Private transport available on request
    </string>
    <string name="addisregencyinfo">Located in old town Addis Ababa near the Piazza.\nAddis Regency Hotel occupies a strategic location for both business and leisure in East Africas most dynamic and beloved city. While its convenience for business travelers is unrivaled, it is also within easy walking distance of the Piazza shopping strip, the National Museum, St. George Cathedral and a number of major Addis Ababa tourist attractions.
        \n
        Winner of Trip Advisors 2014 Certificate of Excellence, Addis Regency Hotel offers 33 guest rooms, including conjoining Family Suites. The hotel has an intimate footprint with 33 guestrooms, a rooftop terrace, events hall and an intimate lobby bar and restaurant.
        \n
        <b>Stay with us and become part of the family!</b></string>
    <string name="agpalaceinfo"><b>Ag Palace Hotel</b>\n We are a small quality driven hotel found in the heart of the Ethiopian capital, Addis Ababa, also known as the capital city of Africa: where leaders are looking for a convenient venue to hold serious discussions and take decisions that will impact millions of people.

Ag Palace hotel offers a choice of both full hotel service operations as well as self catering facilities. Our portfolio includes standard hotel rooms, deluxe hotel suites and single rooms .

Ag Palace is ideal for business travelers, leisure, stopovers, long stays and transits.

At Ag Palace we provide a variety of choices. Whether you are a discerning budget traveler or just looking for that element of luxury of a 5 star business hotel, we have what you are looking for and best suit your need.

Our hotel provide only the highest levels of comfortable quality accommodations and conference facilities and we are the perfect choice for your next visit to Addis Ababa.

We look forward to welcoming you as our best valued Ag Palace guests.</string>
    <string name="getfaminfo">Getfam Hotel is a four star hotel located in the heart of Ethiopia capital city, Addis Ababa. Renowned for its unmatched service quality, comfortable accommodation, spacious venues for events and a highly dedicated staff, Getfam Hotels is the ideal place to stay with its central location close to the commercial shopping centers, airport and African Union.
\n

When you’re here, you’re Family
A Prime Location to Host Your Events

With our commitment to serve the guests with premium service quality and ensure their convenient stay, Getfam also offers spacious and evocative venues for varying business conference, meetings, events and wedding purposes.

The ideal venue with rich interiors, state of the art technologies and facilities, scrumptious food and elegant ambiance, all events are planned by our courteous team with meticulous detailing down to the last point.

    </string>
    <string name="nazrainfo">Nazra Hotel offers 4-star Addis Ababa hotel accommodations 1.3 mi or 2 km from “Red Terror” Martyrs\' Memorial Museum and 1.5 mi or 2.5 km from Meskel Square.
        ECA Conference Center and Addis Ababa Stadium are also within 2 mi or 3 km.

        Along with free buffet breakfast, this hotel offers a restaurant and free self parking. The on-site spa is the place to be for rest and relaxation, offering facials, a steam room and massages. The bar/lounge is a perfect place to have a drink. In addition to the on-site spa, a fitness center, a spa tub and a sauna are among the leisure facilities on offer.

Knowledgeable staff available at the front desk 24 hours-a-day and can provide tour/ticket assistance, express check-in and express check-out. Guests can make use of the free WiFi. </string>
    <string name="radissonbluinfo">The Radisson Blu Hotel, Addis Ababa hotel is in the city center within walking distance of the United Nations Conference Center (UNCC). Our Addis Ababa hotel offers easy access to the city’s major businesses and organizations, including the ECA Conference Centre and Unicef Ethiopia, and is just a 15-minute drive from Bole International Airport (ADD). Business delegates</string>
    <string name="sheratonaaddisinfo">Set in mountainous countryside, 7,800 feet above sea level, the Sheraton Addis is the first hotel in Africa to join The Luxury Collection. The hotel is conveniently located near the capital\'s main attractions, including the National Palace and the Merkato, one of the largest open air markets in Africa. Elegant guest rooms, exceptional recreational and meeting facilities and an extraordinary selection of fine restaurants make the Sheraton Addis the ideal African luxury destination.
    ROOM FEATURES
Discover what luxury really means. We offer 294 deluxe guest rooms - including 33 suites, 20 classic suites, nine junior suites, and four luxurious executive suites. For our most distinguished guests, a magnificent self-contained villa - featuring a private swimming pool and gymnasium - provides an even greater level of privacy and elegance. For added convenience, each room features a private safe and 24-hour room service.

» Fax Machine
» Individual Climate Control
» In-Room Safe
» Private Balcony
» Starwood Preferred Guest Rooms Available
» Non-Smoking Rooms Available
» Suites Available
» Villas Available 	» Deluxe Bath Amenities
» Hairdryer in Room
» Garden View Rooms Available
» Maid Service
» Air-Conditioned Rooms
» City View Rooms Available
» Butler Service
» Connecting Rooms Available

Some of the amenities above may not be available in all rooms.
    HOTEL FACILITIES AND AMENITIES

Designed to cater to the most demanding requirements, the Sheraton Addis offers a complete selection of services and facilities. Our state-of-the-art business center provides unrivaled service and a dedicated, professional staff. Wide ranges of recreational facilities are also available, as well as many exclusive personal services.
Come and discover The Aqva Club, designed in ageless beauty and providing an atmosphere of relaxation with attentive services. This recreational facility includes outdoor swimming pools featuring underwater music, sauna, massage, and Jacuzzi.

» Outdoor Heated Pool
» Massage Treatments
» Sauna
» Business Center/Services
» Outdoor Children\'s Pool
» Free Airport Pick-Up and Drop-Off (Limited)
» 24-Hour Room Service
» 24-Hour Front Desk
» Translation Services
» Computer Rental
» Copy/Printing Service
» Wake-up Service Available 	» Air-Conditioned Facilities
» Bars
» Car Rental Service
» Doorman
» Free Parking Facilities
» Ice Machine
» Live Entertainment
» Lounges
» Night Club
» Restaurants
» Secretarial Service
» Shopping Nearby
We are proud to offer the largest and most prestigious banquet and conference facilities in Ethiopia, providing over 1,500 square meters of meeting space. In order to meet your individual needs, the nine main meeting rooms can be subdivided into 12 smaller rooms and include the magnificent Lalibela Grand Ballroom with a capacity of up to 1,500 guests.

All facilities are equipped with the latest audio/visual equipment and conference phone line, and offer sophisticated simultaneous translation capabilities. Meeting spaces are complemented by generous pre-function areas. Our expert banquet and meeting staff are available to assist with planning and organization.
</string>
    <string name="theresidenceinfo"> The Residence Suite Hotel

The Residence Suite Hotel – is a charming, distinct property with an even more distinct character. With a range of accommodation options available, be it a long or a short stay, The Residence suites cater to all!

Comfort and personalized service are key attributes that have been given extra attention at The Residence. The spacious suites are tastefully designed to the highest level of comfort and are more of a self contained studio, equipped with a working desk, seating area, Plasma screen TVs, complimentary Tea/Coffee facilities and snacks iron/iron boards, safes, microwave and small kitchenettes*. Suites have also pampering extras like complimentary mineral water, bathrobes and slippers, organic locally made soaps and DVD players*.

A sleek, simple restaurant serves a sumptuous complimentary breakfast and caters local and international selections to any desired snack, lunch or dinner.

Situated in the exclusive most sought after area of Olympia, this is an ideal choice of accommodation for business and leisure guests where financial institutions, shopping, major local and foreign organizations are within close proximity.

So whether it is Addis Ababa your business or leisure destination, or you are passing through towards a further destination, when it comes to a lovely stay experience, your search ends here
</string>
    <string name="jupiterinfo">Jupiter International Hotels, a four star hotel with two superb locations in Addis Ababa to serve you better. Our largest property located in the Cazanchise area is a walking distance from the UNECA center on Marshal Tito Road. Our second property in Bole is situated moments away from the airport and located near major shopping centers.</string>
    <string name="stgabriel">St Gabriel Hospital
    Address: 22 Mazoria, infront of Awraris Hotel,
Bole Sub city, House No. 376/U
Telephone: +251 6 187345, +251 911 434384
Fax: +251 116 614540
P. O. Box: 5634
Email: mekete45@yahoo.com
Website:
www.saintgabrielgeneralhospital.com
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, French, Amharic
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned general
hospital, with experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services and Insurance payment
must be abided by agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: Body Detox treatment (UNIQUE),
Pharmacy, Ambulance, Morgue</string>
    <string name="taphemedicalservice">Tebita Ambulance Pre-Hospital Emergency Medical Service
    Address: Infront of Addis Hiwot Hopsital or behind
Gethun Besha Bldg, Bole Sub city, House No. 168
Telephone: Emergency 8035, +251 911 225464,
+251 911 641609
Fax: 0116616342
P. O. Box:
Email: kibret1@yahoo.com
Website: www.tebitaambulance.com
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned prehospital emergency medical service, with the
experience of treating British nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services must be abided by
agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: We provide treatment with fully
equipped ambulance (eg. AED, Respirator) and
with professional staff.</string>
    <string name="asterhos">Aster Primary Hospital
    Aster Primary Hospital--Hawassa
Address: Hawassa, Menaharia Subcity
Telephone: 0462206153
Fax: NA
P. O. Box: 1826
Email: asherhosp1998@yahoo.com
Website: NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned primary
hospital, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash (both local and foreign
currency) and credit system are available. Credit
services must be abided by agreement prior to
treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: Pharmacy, Ambulance, Morgue</string>
    <string name="bethalhos">Bethel Hospital
Address: Kolfekeranyo Subcity, Weyira Area,
Wereda 8
Telephone: +251 3 495475-78
Fax: +251 3 495839
P. O. Box: 9011
Email: info@bethelhospital.com
Website: www.bethelethiohospital.com
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic, Korean
Translators: Somali, English, Oromifa
Hospital details: it is a privately owned general
hospital, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services and Insurance payment
must be abided by agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: We have Pharmacy, Ambulance,
Morgue, and Med Pharm.</string>
    <string name="delthos">Delt General Hospital—Dire Dawa
Address: Dire Dawa, Sabian area, Kebele 02, Circle
Hotel
Telephone: 025 113 0996, 025 112 1194, +251 946
439329
Fax: 025 113 0998
P. O. Box: NA
Email: delthospital@gmail.com
Website: NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic, Somali, French,
Arabic
Translators: one per each OPD for the above
languages
Hospital details: it is a privately owned primary
hospital, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services and insurance payment
services must be abided by agreement prior to
treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: Pharmacy, Ambulance, and Morgue are
available.</string>
    <string name="dremebethos">Dr. Emebet Special Dental Clinic
Address: Yeka Subcity, Near British Embassy,
Wereda 05, House No.
Telephone: +251 6 674201/03, +251 911 404917
Fax: NA
P. O. Box: NA
Email: NA
Website:
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic, Indian, Korean,
Pilipino, Spanish,
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned special
dental clinic.
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Foreign currency is accepted according
to the day’s rate.
Visiting hours: 8am to 7pm</string>
    <string name="redcrooss">Ethiopian Red Cross Society
Address: Near national stadium, House No. NA
Telephone: Emergency 8035, 907,
+251 5 519364, +251 5 519144
Fax: 0115512643
P. O. Box: 195
Email: ercsinfo@redcrosseth.org
Website: www.redcrosseth.org
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a humanitarian organization.
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available.
Visiting hours: 24hrs</string>
    <string name="felegehiwothos">Felegehiwot Referral Hospital—Bahir Dar
Address: Bahir Dar, in front Police Commission,
Kebele 13,
Telephone: +251 918 70 2941, +251
Fax: 058 222 0917
P. O. Box: 47
Email: ebrumar2@yahoo.com
Website: www.fhrh.org.et
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic,
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a governmental hospital, with
the experience of treating British nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services must be abided by
agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: Pharmacy and Morgue are available.</string>
    <string name="hayathos">Hayat Hospital
Address: Bole Subcity, Wereda 03/05,
Telephone: +251 116 624488, +251 116 614250
Email: hayathosp@ethionet.et
Website: NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Oromifa, Amharic, Arabic
Beginner
Hospital details: it is a privately owned general
hospital, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services and Insurance
payment must be abided by agreement prior to
treatment. Visiting hours: 24hours
Remark: Kidney Dialysis treatment (UNIQUE).
Ambulance, Morgue]</string>
    <string name="kadiscohos">Kadisco General Hospital
Address: Bole Subcity, Gerji Area, Wereda 11
Telephone: +251 6 298902/03/04
Fax: +251 116 298757
P. O. Box: 120919
Email: kgh@kadcogroup.com
Website: www.kadcogroup.com/kgh
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, French, Amharic
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned general
hospital, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash (both local and foreign
currency) and credit system are available. Credit
services and Insurance payment must be abided
by agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: UV Treatment (UNIQUE), Pharmacy,
Ambulance, Morgue</string>
    <string name="kibruhos">Kibru Primary Hospital--Hawassa
Address: Hawassa, Menaharia Subcity, Piassa
Kebele
Telephone: 046 2 210950, 0911 404882
Fax: NA
P. O. Box: 948
Email: yidnekw@gmail.com
Website: NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned primary
hospital, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash (both local and foreign
currency) and credit system are available. Credit
services must be abided by agreement prior to
treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: Pharmacy, Ambulance</string>
    <string name="koreanhos">Korean Hospital
Address: Bole Subcity, Wereda 14,
Telephone: +251 116 295428, +251 116 295420-
25
Email: msmcmet@gmail.com
Website:NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Korean, Amharic
Translators: Chinese, Local Somali
Hospital details: it is a privately owned general
hospital, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services and Insurance payment
must be abided by agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hours
Remark: Fast Track/Clinic (UNIQUE) that gives a
quick/direct service which they would pay three
times more than the normal price.
On July 2015, VIP Ward will be opened. This ward
will serve patients that used to travel abroad for
treatments that are not available here in Ethiopia.
Eg, Cardiac, MRI,
 Pharmacy, Ambulance, Morgue are also
available</string>
    <string name="rankspecclinic">Rank Specialized Higher Clinic (known for
skin treatment)
Address: Kirkos Subcity, Wollsefer area, Wereda
02, House No. 806
Telephone: +251 5 536074/75, +251 912 140412
Fax: NA
P. O. Box: 40365
Email: NA
Website: NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic,
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned
specialized higher clinic.
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services must be abided by
agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 8:30am to 8pm
Remark: Photethrapy, cryotheraphy and peel
treatment.</string>
    <string name="santehos">Sante Medical Centre
Address: Kirkos Subcity, Legehar next to Shipping
Libes Bldg. Area, Wereda 07
Telephone: +251 5 535526/30, +251 912 613161
Fax: +251 5 506528
P. O. Box: 25892 Code 1000
Email: santemedical.sante@gmail.com
Website: www.santemedicalcenter.org
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Arabic, Amharic
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned medical
canter, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services must be abided by
agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: Pharmacy, Ambulance, Morgue are
available and they are known for Kidney
treatment and nephrologists (Unique)</string>
    <string name="selassieclinci">Selassie Clinic
Address: Arada Subcity, Ginfile/ Ambachew Bldg
Area, house no 552/1, Kebele 13/14, Wereda 07
Telephone: +251 1 242020, +251 911 214874
Fax: NA
P. O. Box: 32919
Email: melakuferede@gmail.com
Website: NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic, Oromoifa
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned higher
clinic, with the experience of treating British
nationals
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services and Insurance payment
must be abided by agreement prior to
treatment.
Visiting hours: 8:30am to 8pm
Remark: We have CDC machine, Photometer,
and we provide emergency drug</string>
    <string name="teklehaimanothos">Teklehaimanot General Hospital
Address: Arada Subcity, Somali Tera infront of
Global Insurance, Wereda 01
Telephone: +251 1 561287, +251 1 561114, +251
940 333333
Fax: +251 1 562801
P. O. Box: 2407
Email: tgh@ethionet.et
Website: NA
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic,
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a privately owned general
hospital.
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services and Insurance payment
must be abided by agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: We have Pharmacy (24hrs), Ambulance
(24hrs), Morgue.</string>
    <string name="wagaclinic">Wagga Special Eye Clinic
Address: Bole Subcity, telemedhaniyalem area,
Wereda 03, House No. 074
Telephone: +251 6 180186, +251 8 296566 +251
931 520952
Fax: NA
P. O. Box: 17264
Email: NA
Website: www.wggamedical.com
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic,
Translators: NA
Hospital details: it is a share company,
specialized clinic.
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. Credit services must be abided by
agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 8:30am to 6pm
Remark: No appointment needed for
treatment. Most doctors are specialized.</string>
    <string name="washingtonhos">Washington medical Centre
Address: Bole Subcity, infronet of Rwanda
Embassy, Wereda 02, House No. 692
Telephone: +251 6 635969, +251 939
515151/525252
Fax: +251 6 635968
P. O. Box: 535/1110
Email: wmc@wmcaddis.com
Website: www.wmcaddis.com
This company has told us the following things:
Languages: English, Amharic,
Translators: Somali
Hospital details: it is a privately owned medical
centre.
Payment System: Cash and credit system are
available. VISA and Master card accepted. Credit
services and Insurance payment must be abided
by agreement prior to treatment.
Visiting hours: 24hrs
Remark: We have US Board Certified Doctors,
Pharmacy, Ambulance, and Morgue. Electronic
medical recording system and state of the art
medical equipments.</string>
    <string name="adinetSchool">Andinet International School is a collegium of students and
teachers working together to build a culture that promotes
creative problem solving, critical thinking, and academic
excellence, and that embraces unity, integrity, and inclusion.
The AIS family nurtures and encourages children to challenge
themselves academically and creatively in a supportive
environment. We believe in children. We believe in our children
Our Address: Andinet International School
Yeka Subcity, Woreda 9, House Number New
Addis Ababa , Ethiopia.
Mailing Address : Andinet International School
P.O. Box 1289
Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Phone: +251 11 6479989
+251 11 8603763
Email: ais@ethionet.et
</string>
    <string name="binghamschool">Bingham Academy is an international school located in Addis Ababa ,
Ethiopia .
History
What became Bingham Academy was first established in 1946 as
the "Home and School for Missionary\'s Children" (SMC). In 1952 it
moved from its original location in Eas Dairu to its present location
in Kolfe . Over the years it has had a various number of different
grades, starting with Grade 1 to 8 in 1946 to the current Kindergarten
to 12. but we have changed Kindergarten by cutting them into 2
rooms for Kg1 and Kg2
It was rated amongst the top 100 secondary schools by Africa
Alamanac in 2003. [1]
Address:
Bingham Academy, Box 4937, Addis
Ababa, ETHIOPIA Phone: +251 112
791 791
</string>
    <string name="britishschool">
Sandford International School was known until the recent change of name as the Sandford English (Community) School.

The origins of the school can be traced back to the early 1940s when Mrs. Christine Sandford, wanted to establish an English-speaking school for her children. The English –speaking community was very small at the time but the Ethiopian nobility also wanted access to an English education for their children. Christine Sandford was the wife of Colonel Sandford, the Head of British Military Mission to Ethiopia during World War II, who along with Cunningham and Wingate, led the British contingent that was dispatched by the British Government to help Emperor Haile Selassie I and the Ethiopian army reclaim the country from 5 year of Italian occupation under Mussolini’s Government.

Partly in gratitude for their assistance and partly because Colonel Sandford liked Ethiopia very much and returned here to live with his family, as close friends of the Emperor and the restored government, the Sandford family was granted land for farming and for building a school. The small English Speaking community had no suitable educational facilities, nor did the British Embassy families who often wanted their children here with them instead of back home in England or boarded in Kenya or Cairo, the options at the time.

Sandford School grew rapidly, and in a manner befitting the founders and their interest in living in Ethiopia and educating their children along with Ethiopian children. From the beginning, as agreed with the Imperial Government, the school was open to Ethiopians with a reduced, subsidized system of fees to allow the attendance of Ethiopian children, including children of the Royal and other leading families. There was thus a development of education component meant to benefit the whole country, not only the few British families.


Address: Addis Ababa Ethiopia.
P.O Box:  30056 MA,
Phone: +251 111 233726 / 27 / 29  /  Fax: +251 111 233728
E-mail: info@sandfordschool.org  /  sandford@ethionet.et
</string>
    <string name="greekschool">Company name
Greek Community School
Address
598, Addis Ababa , Ethiopia
Phone
011 551 0274
Info:
Greek school is a multi-classed school in addis ababa, Ethiopia.
GREEK COMMUNITY SCHOOL IS LOCATED
IN ADDIS ABABA, ETHIOPIA.
THE PURPOSE OF THIS WEB SITE IS TO
NETWORK ALL THE EX-STUDENTS OF
G.C.S THAT RESIDE AROUND THE WORLD.
Once home to a thriving Greek community of
over 4,000; the military takeover of the
Ethiopia in 1974 caused many Greeks to
leave. Some stayed behind and maintained
many of the institutions that were set up by
their forefathers, including the prominent
Greek school of Addis Ababa.
Home today to 120 students, 80 of which
live in the borading house, the school
conducts classes in all Greek and learn
everything from Greek georgraphy, to history
and philosophy.  While students have to
prove some Greek blood to enroll, (how do
you prove that?) the school has done a great
job in maintaining the connection with
Greece dispite the distance and wars that
have ravaged Ethiopia the past few decades.
Many of the students end up receiving
scholorships to eventually go and study in
Greece.
</string>
    <string name="interncommschool">International Community School of
Addis Ababa
The International Community School of Addis Ababa founded in 1964, is an
Independent, co-educational day school that teaches students of all
Nationalities in early childhood through grade 12 and is located in
Addis Ababa, the capital city of Ethiopia. The school was founded as
the American Community School, but changed to its current name in
the 1978-79 school year.
For the 2014-15 school year, the faculty consists of 97
professionally certified teachers from 14 countries: USA, Germany,
India, United kingdom, Australia, Ireland, South Africa, Bulgaria,
Peru,Kenya, Ethiopia, Canada, Fiji and France.
In 2014-15, the school\'s enrollment is 846 students, from over 67
nations.The school has been accredited by the Middle States
Association of Colleges and Schools since 1992. In 2006 the school
was reaccredited through December 2014 and the school has gone
through re-accreditation process in May 2014. ICS Addis has been
authorized to offer the International Baccalaureate Diploma Program
(IBDP) since March 1982.
Address:
INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY SCHOOL OF ADDIS ABABA
Mauritania Road - Old Airport, PO Box 70282, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
(251) 11-371-1544
info@icsaddis.edu.et
</string>
    <string name="turkishschool">The British International School, Secondary Section occupies The Sherif Building on the Bole Ring Road 5 minutes drive from Addis Ababa International Airport. The Kindergarten and Primary Sections are conveniently situated in Gerji, also near the airport.
Our school community includes students from more than 46 countries of the world, with a minimum age of 3 years  on September 1st.
Address: Mauritania St, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Phone:+251 11 371 1544

</string>
    <string name="oneplanetschool">One Planet International School PLC (One Planet) is one of the few premium schools in Addis Ababa, entirely owned by the Gail and Zelalem Amare family. It was founded in 2006 with just over 30 kindergarten students. Adding one more class in each of the following years, the school now serves around 450 students from Kindergarten through tenth grades. One Planet has low student-to-teacher ratios: Class sizes are no larger than 20 for kindergarten and no larger than 24 for grades 1 through 10.
While living in America, Zelalem and Gail had a desire to return to Africa and contribute to the social and economic development of Ethiopia.
With five children of their own, they decided that they could best contribute to Ethiopia’s future and their own children’s future, by opening a school with a holistic approach to education which focuses on both academic excellence and character development.
Why “One Planet”? We are all citizens of a common planet.  No matter where we were born, what we look like, what language we speak, or what we ate for breakfast… we are all the same people.  Our goal at One Planet is to recognize that we are all one people of one planet.  We not only need to treat each other with dignity and respect, but we need to take care of our home, planet Earth!
ADDRESS:
One Planet International School, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia-Near Megenagna, +251-116-18-10-10 , +251-910-99-07-65, +251- 912- 79-46-53
</string>
    <string name="riceschool">The idea for Reach International Center of Education (RICE) was conceived in the early months of 2012 arising from two sparks. The first spark was seeing yet again the demand by parents for an education that will both prepare their child academically, but one which will also lay a solid moral and ethical foundation, developing a child’s character; a character especially moulded with Christian values. The second spark was the desire to provide quality international education that would encourage Ethiopians living abroad to return to Ethiopia. Ethiopians who live overseas or have been studying overseas with their families are often concerned about the education of their children when returning. This concern has unfortunately resulted in many families deciding to remain overseas. We would like to see RICE provide one contributing factor for Ethiopians to return to their home country of Ethiopia.
These two sparks ignited an ongoing conversation between Andy, Haimi and Clare about the desirability and possibility of starting an international school that was framed within a Christian environment. After much prayer and deliberation we decided to push the doors and see what God would do. God not only opened doors wide but also in doing so He confirmed to us that the seeds of vision growing within our hearts were indeed set there by God Himself. Within two months all requirements were met in order to obtain the appropriate license from the Investment Agency in Ethiopia.
Beside the expectation of raising the minimum required capital amount of $60,000 was the need to find a suitable facility in which the school could be started. Current land prices and building costs are such that a significant amount of capital would be required if we wanted to buy land and build our own school. But would we find suitable facilities? The same week that we started to push doors we found a local university in Addis Ababa that had a block of classrooms they were looking to rent. Built in the last couple of years but never used, and with green space that could be developed as a play area, we again found God leading us through doors beyond our expectation.
Unfortunately, as so often happens when on a journey with God, we found several challenges facing us in early 2013. The first challenge came with the news that the university were no longer able to rent to us. After the initial shock, we began to look for other property we could rent and were able to narrow our choice down to several houses. However, before signing a lease agreement Andy again enquired at the Investment Agency to ensure there were no ‘surprises’ as we moved forward. Along came the second challenge. We discovered that the Ethiopian Law regarding foreign investment had changed and the minimum capital investment had been changed from $60,000 to a minimum of $150,000.
In February 2013, we therefore decided to postpone starting the school for one year. Though disheartened, we also knew that God’s timing is perfect.
The journey from that decision in 2013 until August 2014 presented many challenges. By the end of that summer we had raised all the required capital through the generous support of many. So we again began to look for a suitable facility in which to start RICE. That turned out to be quite a hurdle. We found one suitably large building towards the western edge of Addis Ababa but the owner was unable to complete the required paperwork despite several months of effort. Another house was found but at the last minute the owner decided not to rent. Then finally in May 2014 we found an old villa house on 1000 square metres of land. Though rather tired looking the house provided everything that we needed to start a school; classroom space, toilets and several play areas. We signed the lease in June 2014. Then began two solid months of hard work turning the house into a school.
ADDRESS:
Postal Address: PO Box 26207 Code 1000, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Physical Address: Nefas Silk/Lafto, Wereda 04, House Number 1832, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Tel: 251-929-951976 or 251-911-670107
Email: riceeethiopia@gmail.com

</string>
    <string name="sanfordschool">The idea for Reach International Center of Education (RICE) was conceived in the early months of 2012 arising from two sparks. The first spark was seeing yet again the demand by parents for an education that will both prepare their child academically, but one which will also lay a solid moral and ethical foundation, developing a child’s character; a character especially moulded with Christian values. The second spark was the desire to provide quality international education that would encourage Ethiopians living abroad to return to Ethiopia. Ethiopians who live overseas or have been studying overseas with their families are often concerned about the education of their children when returning. This concern has unfortunately resulted in many families deciding to remain overseas. We would like to see RICE provide one contributing factor for Ethiopians to return to their home country of Ethiopia.
These two sparks ignited an ongoing conversation between Andy, Haimi and Clare about the desirability and possibility of starting an international school that was framed within a Christian environment. After much prayer and deliberation we decided to push the doors and see what God would do. God not only opened doors wide but also in doing so He confirmed to us that the seeds of vision growing within our hearts were indeed set there by God Himself. Within two months all requirements were met in order to obtain the appropriate license from the Investment Agency in Ethiopia.
Beside the expectation of raising the minimum required capital amount of $60,000 was the need to find a suitable facility in which the school could be started. Current land prices and building costs are such that a significant amount of capital would be required if we wanted to buy land and build our own school. But would we find suitable facilities? The same week that we started to push doors we found a local university in Addis Ababa that had a block of classrooms they were looking to rent. Built in the last couple of years but never used, and with green space that could be developed as a play area, we again found God leading us through doors beyond our expectation.
Unfortunately, as so often happens when on a journey with God, we found several challenges facing us in early 2013. The first challenge came with the news that the university were no longer able to rent to us. After the initial shock, we began to look for other property we could rent and were able to narrow our choice down to several houses. However, before signing a lease agreement Andy again enquired at the Investment Agency to ensure there were no ‘surprises’ as we moved forward. Along came the second challenge. We discovered that the Ethiopian Law regarding foreign investment had changed and the minimum capital investment had been changed from $60,000 to a minimum of $150,000.
In February 2013, we therefore decided to postpone starting the school for one year. Though disheartened, we also knew that God’s timing is perfect.
The journey from that decision in 2013 until August 2014 presented many challenges. By the end of that summer we had raised all the required capital through the generous support of many. So we again began to look for a suitable facility in which to start RICE. That turned out to be quite a hurdle. We found one suitably large building towards the western edge of Addis Ababa but the owner was unable to complete the required paperwork despite several months of effort. Another house was found but at the last minute the owner decided not to rent. Then finally in May 2014 we found an old villa house on 1000 square metres of land. Though rather tired looking the house provided everything that we needed to start a school; classroom space, toilets and several play areas. We signed the lease in June 2014. Then began two solid months of hard work turning the house into a school.
ADDRESS:
Postal Address: PO Box 26207 Code 1000, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Physical Address: Nefas Silk/Lafto, Wereda 04, House Number 1832, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Tel: 251-929-951976 or 251-911-670107
Email: riceeethiopia@gmail.com

</string>
    <string name="abccar">ABC CAR RENTAL
Address
JOMO KENYATA ST, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Phone
(251) 011 552 88 87
Fax
(251) 011 553 63 68
Website
www.abccarrent.com
ABC Budget Car Rental and Tour
ABC Budget is a qualified and enthusiastic Ethiopian tour
operation company, established by an Ethiopian investor
whom has a long and wide experience in the tourism
and car rental industry all across Africa, the Middle East
and Europe.
</string>
    <string name="adikacar">Adika Tour and Travel
Adika Tour and Travel Pvt. Ltd. Co. is a business
undertaking company established in November 2004
with leading and reliable Tour, Travel and Car Rental
Company based in Addis Ababa, the capital of Ethiopia.
Since its establishment, ADIKA is offering efficient and
prompt service to its customers.
ADDRESS/CONTACT:
Phone +251 11 5533357/5536928/5538700
Fax +251 11 5538555
Mobile +251 91 1202046
Kebele 2
House Number 131
Location Addis Ababa
</string>
    <string name="amazingcar">Amazing Ethiopia
Ethiopia is famous for having the most unparalleled
riches and historical legacy in Sub-Saharan Africa.
Referring to the classic historic travel circuit followed to
the south and east, one commonly visits 5 key
destinations: Axum, Lalibela, Gondar, Bahir Dar and
Harar.
ADDRESS/CONTACT:
Address: Bole, Addis Ababa
091 142 7728
</string>
    <string name="homenetcar">Homenet Car Rental and Commission Agent is a leading company
in the car rental and tour operation sector, House rent and sales,
Car sale, Hotel and guest house reservations, Domestic and
international Air ticketing service in Ethiopia. Homenet was
founded in 1999 with an initial capital of less than 10,000 and with
three permanent employees.
Our company succeeded in becoming the best full service firm in a
short time in Ethiopia with a capital of more than one million birr
and with fifty five permanent human resources. Our company had
contributed a a great deal to the car rental and tour operation
sector in providing a reliable and quality service to clients.
Homenet is established expertly to serve the market competently
and capably.
Phone +251 11 6611414
Phone 2 +251 11 6621464
Phone 3 +25111 6181416
Fax +251 11 6181411
Mobile +251 91 1233272
Business Type Private
Location Bole in front of the European Union,
Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
</string>
    <string name="rainbowcar">Welcome to Rainbow Exclusive Car Rental and
Tour Services
Rainbow Exclusive Car Rental and Tour Service is a
member of the MIDROC Ethiopia Technology Group
located in Addis Ababa, and is one of the leading
tour and car rental services providers in Ethiopia. We
are well known for our excellent service in tour
operation, car rental and hotel reservation throughout
Ethiopia.
Rainbow Exclusive Car Rental and Tour Service is
the most reliable and tailor made tour provider in
Ethiopia with a well organized structure, that holds
one of the most highly and well trained management
staff, tour operators, guides, cooks and vehicles in
the country. We have an efficient, courteous and
experienced staff who are acquainted with customer
relations and handling. Rainbow believes in providing
exclusive services with a goal of being “Second –to-
None” .
Our vehicles are reliable and insured for your
personal comfort and safety. Our corresponding
sister companies such as, the Sheraton Addis Hotel
and Mugad Travel also work mutually with us to
make your visit to Ethiopia memorable.
ADDRESS:
Phone +251-011-371 7944
+251-011-371 7940
Fax +251-011-371 1424
Address Nifas Silk Lafto Sub-City, Kebele
04, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
</string>
    <string name="senaitcar">SENAIT ETHIOPIA TOURS
http://www.senaitethiopia.com
E-mail: info@senaitethiopia.com
011 629 4039
Mob.: 0930 014 376
Fax : 011 629 4050
P.O. Box: 29977
Email: info@senaitethiopia.com
Email: info@sunnyethiopiatours.com
Website : www.senaitethiopia.com
Senait Ethiopia Tour
meaning \'Beautiful Ethiopia, Excellent Ethiopia\' in
Amharic, the official language of Ethiopia, is a private
Ethiopian owned tour company which has been
operating since 2008 that offers wide selections of tour
package, tailor-made and customized tours throughout
the beautiful and sunny country of Ethiopia.
 </string>
    <string name="shangerilacar">Shangerila Ethiopia Tours
With its young tourism professionals and multilingual
tour guides, drivers and cooks, Shangerila Ethiopia
Tours is bringing a turning point to the country’s
tourism industry. Moreover, the company is engaged in
the printing of high quality post cards and posters on
various tourist attractions,
ADDRESS/CONTACT:
Location Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
Phone +251 116 629931
Fax +251 116 629932
Mobile +251 912 600660
</string>
    <string name="zelalemcar">Zelalem Tours
We proudly present our product Ker-Ezhi Ethiopia Tour
Guide Magazine is available for all your android devices.
You can go to Google play and search for the key work
Ker-Ezhi to find all available issues of the magazine. It is
free and suitable for your mobile devices, tablet or
android OS laptops.
ADDRESS/CONTACT:
Address: Gambia St, Addis Ababa
091 120 9106
</string>

</resources>
